#### **LUCAS MONTANO**

meu-email@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/lucasmontano/en https://github.com/lucasmontano

# PERSONAL STATEMENT

Working with mobile development since 2011, I have co-founded and developed multiple apps which impact 1.5 Million consumers in more than 23 countries. Always concerned with the User Experience and using data-metrics to reach high retention rates.

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Senior Android Engineer

At Speakap

October 2018 - Present

Speakap is an internal communications platform that enables organizations to reach, involve and connect all employees - regardless of their physical location within the business.

- I've been working together with the product team and stakeholders, developing new features and scaling the app up to 400.000 users.
- Migrating the architecture from MVC to MVVM, using concepts of UI state, immutability, reactive programming with rxJava and one source of truth with the unidirectional data flow.
- Data security along with user experience are very important aspects in our product. I had the opportunity to implement encryption using Android Keystore with backcompatibility until Lollipop.

## **Senior Android Engineer**

At Descartaê

January 2018 - August 2018

Defining the android architecture of this amazing Open Source project from scratch, thinking about what would fit best for the community to jump in.

- The decision to use Graphql instead of REST had brought extreme flexibility and efficiency;
- Helping the product owner to specify the main features and the best User Experience for the platform.

#### Co-Founder & Senior Android Developer

At Planejei

May 2015 - October 2018

Establishing the business strategy and working side by side with our Chief Product Officer in the definition of Product Roadmap and User Experience.

- We have been impacting more than 25.000 Brazilians lives, helping better manage money.
- A data-driven team using Crashlytics, Mixpanel to achieve high standard relation rates.
- I've been coding with TDD, JUnit, Mockito, reaching a coverage rate of 64%.
- Implementing Cloud Test, and Cloud Messaging with Firebase.

#### **Mobile Solutions Architect**

At Hewlett-Packard

September 2014 - April 2015

I had the opportunity to accept the challenge to bring agile methodology to a big project with the biggest client which in the period was using water flow methodology.

- Defining the overall technical architecture for the mobile applications projects.
- Engaging developers to use the appropriate design patterns, libs, and implement TDD.

## Senior Android Developer

At Superplayer

May 2014 - September 2014

Helped the company to achieve their first goal after received a Series A round from Movile, develop the native Android app in 100 days. Extremely data-driven was amazing to work with Gustavo, the CEO.

## Founder & Senior Full-Stack Developer

At Moolab

September 2012 - November 2015

I started Moolab with the mission to transform good ideas into amazing consumer products. Analyzing the technical viability and market fit with stakeholders. Helped clients in the definition of objectives key results (OKR) and growth metrics.

# Senior Full-Stack Developer & Tech Leader

At TargetIT

February 2010 - December 2012

# **EDUCATION**

#### **Bachelor of Computer Information Systems**

**ULBRA** (Lutheran University of Brazil)

June 2008 - June 2014

# Management, Entrepreneurship

**CNEC** 

2005 - 2007

# OTHER PROJECTS

# Co-Founder & Board Member

Agreg.io

November 2017 - Present

Enabling financial institutions to connect with user's bank accounts, helping them bring innovative solutions to market more quickly using high-quality consumers data as transaction history and finance behavior.

#### Founder & Solo Android Engineer

Finanças Pessoais

May 2011 - Present

My first app, a personal finance manager, reached 1.000.000 downloads at Google Play, supporting 20 countries in 5 languages.